A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, President, Malcolm Aldrich papers, SG 3, Series 7 FA1464
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, President, Malcolm Aldrich papers, SG 3, Series 7
1919-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
Aldrich, Malcolm
FA1464
2 Cubic Feet 4 letter-size document boxes and 1 legal-size document box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
The Malcolm P. Aldrich papers primarily serve to provide historical context to the work and activities of the Commonwealth Fund. The series includes historical sketches of the Harkness Fellowship Program, as well as the Fund's Publications department. The records also include select Board of Directors files as well as program reviews and recommendations. Aldrich also served as the executor of the Harkness estate, and the series contains a variety of historical files pertaining to the Harkness family.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. The initial transfer of archival records to RAC began in 1986, and transfers continue on a regular basis. This series was donated to RAC as part of the initial transfer in 1985.
Biographical / Historical
Malcolm P. Aldrich served as the second President of the Commonwealth Fund, succeeding Edward S. Harkness, and Chairman of the Fund's Board. As head of the Fund he actively promoted medical education and facilitated the builing of a new wing at the Eye Institute at Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center.
- Malcolm P. Aldrich - Commonwealth Fund Financials, 1931-1948, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Commonwealth Fund - Annual Report - Summary 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Estate of Mary S. Harkness, 1947-1952, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Edward S. Harkness (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Investment Book (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mary S. Harkness - Obituary, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hedges Inn - East Hampton, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Contributions - Edward S. Harkness and Mary S. Harkness, 1932-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Portage Lake Mining Company - Stock (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mary Harkness Convalescent Home (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Save the Redwoods League, 1925-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Malcolm Aldrich Correspondence and Activities, 1960-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Harkness Estate (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Harkness Family Home - Bellevue, OH - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Recommendations and Reports to the Commonwealth Fund Directors-Board of Directors, 1957-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- A. McGhee Harvey - History of the Commonwealth Fund, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Harkness Fellows, 1964-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- S. Gorley Putt, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Harkness Fellowships, 1947-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- History of the Harkness Fellowship Program, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Commonwealth Fund Board of Directors, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Eye Institute, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Harvard University - Correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center Fund, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Commonwealth Fund History of Publications Department, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Commonwealth Fund By-Laws, 1963-1981 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Commonwealth Fund Board Meetings and Minutes, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center Fund - Contributions and Pledges, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Commonwealth Fund Program Areas, 1931-1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Harkness Fellowship Program, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Commonwealth Fund Board of Directors Files, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Commonwealth Fund Board of Directors Files, 1966-1984 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Commonwealth Fund Program Reviews and Recommendations, 1960s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Commonwealth Fund Finance Committee Meeting, 1975 November 19 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Commonwealth Fund Record of Investments, 1919-1953, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)